Tampere, Finland +358504805190 junsheng.fu@tut.fi

Junsheng Fu

GitHub Patents Homepage

I am an experienced researcher, a quick learner and a problem solver, passionate about autonomous driving, with 8 patents applications and 4 papers. I like to think "what if" and "how to", and enjoy applying Computer Vision and Deep Learning techniques to solve the challenges in autonomous driving.

Technical skills

Languages: Python, Matlab, C/C++

Frameworks: TensorFlow, Keras, CUDA, OpenCV, Scikit-learn,

Others: Camera pose estimation, Structure-from-motion, Machine Learning, Tracking, SLAM, Git, Linux

Projects

Sensor fusion-based tracking

Demo

5.2017

- Designed and implemented an Extended Kalman Filter for object tracking with C++.
- · Utilized fused sensor data from both LIDAR and RADAR sensors.

Vehicle detection <u>Demo</u> 4.2017

- · Created vehicle detection and tracking pipeline with two approaches, deep neural networks (YOLO+TensorFlow) and support vector machines (HOG+OpenCV).
- Optimized and evaluated the model on video data from both highway and city driving.

Lane departure warning

Demo

3.2017

- Designed and implemented a lane-finding algorithm and a lane-departure-warning system.
- · Identified lane curvature and overcame environmental challenges, e.g. shadows, pavement changes.

Driving behavioral cloning

Demo

2.2017

- Built and trained a CNN to autonomously steer a car in a game simulator, using TensorFlow and Keras.
- Used optimization techniques such as regularization and dropout to generalize the network for driving on unseen tracks.

Experience

Tampere University of Technology

Doctoral Student

Finland | 1.2014-12.2017

- Implemented 6 autonomous driving demos with OpenCV and TensorFlow (videos).
- · Working on camera pose estimation with LIDAR and street-view images.
- Served as teaching Assistant for "SGN-13006 Introduction to Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning", and got the best course reviews award from students in 2016 Fall Semester.

Nokia Research Center (Nokia Tech) Computer Vision Researcher

Finland | 3.2012-12.2015

- Designed and implemented a 3D Map Augmented Photo gallery application with HERE Map (video).
- Developed an Interactive Video Playback System with HERE Map (video).
- · Implemented 3D reconstruction and visualization systems for indoor 3D smart sensing.

Tampere University of Technology

Research Assistant

Finland | 9.2010-12.2011

- Designed and implemented a real-time video denoising filter with C.
- Embedded a denoising filter into H.264/AVC codecs.

Demola

Software Engineer

Finland | 3.2010-8.2010

· Implemented a face tracking application in Nokia N900 mobile phone with OpenCV and QT.

Education

Tampere University of Technology, Finland - Computer Vision, Ph.D.	GPA: 4.83 / 5	2017
Tampere University of Technology, Finland - Signal Processing, M.Sc.	GPA: 4.45 / 5	2012
Hangzhou Dianzi University, China - Telecommunication, B.Eng.	GPA: 85 / 100	2009
Udacity - Self-Driving-Car Engineer Nanodegree		2017

Patents & Publications

- US 20160248985, Device with an Adaptive Camera Array, published 2016 (link).
- WO 2016102768 A1, Monitoring, published 2016 (<u>link</u>)
- EP 3051410 A1, An apparatus and associated methods for provision of wireless power, published 2016 (<u>link</u>)
- US 20160191796, Methods And Apparatuses For Directional View In Panoramic Content, published 2016 (link)
- US 20150155009, Method And Apparatus For Media Capture Device Position Estimate- Assisted Splicing Of Media, published 2015 (<u>link</u>)
- US 20140300775, Method and Apparatus for Determining Camera Location Information and/or Camera Pose Information According to a Global Coordinate System, published 2016 (link)
- US 20150109508, Method And Apparatus For Generating A Media Capture Request Using Camera Pose Information, published 2015 (link)
- J. Fu, L. Fan, K. Roimela, Y. You, and V.-V. Mattila: "A 3d Map Augmented Photo Gallery Application on Mobile Device", IEEE ICIP 2014, France (link)
- J. Fu, J.-K. Kämäräinen, A. Buch, and N. Krüger: "Indoor Objects and Outdoor Urban Scenes Recognition by 3D Visual Primitives", ACCV workshop 2014, Singapore (link)
- J. Fu, L. Fan, Y. You, and K. Roimela: "Augmented and Interactive Video Playback Based on Global Camera Pose", the 21st ACM Multimedia, 2013, Spain (link).
- L. Fan, J. Fu, Y. You, K. Roimela, P. Piippo and V.-V. Mattila, "Deja Vu: A 3D map augmented photo gallery application on mobile devices", In IEEE ICCV 2013, Demo session, Australia.
- J. Fu, E. Belyaev and K. Egiazarian: "Rate-distortion Oriented Joint Video Pre-filtering and Compression", the 10th conference of FRUCT, 2011, Finland (link).
- Junsheng Fu, Master Thesis 2011: A Real-Time Rate-Distortion Oriented Join Video Denoising and Compression Algorithm (<u>link</u>).

Honors and Activities

TUT Graduate School Scholarship	2016-2017
Nokia Foundation Scholarship	2014
Sisu Award, NRC Multimedia Technology Lab	2013
Runner-up in IIDA Idea Innovation Competition	2011
Outstanding Graduate Award	2009
Chairman of Tampere Chinese Student and Scholar Association	2014-2015
Chairman of one Badminton Club in Tampere	2012